Here in Avonlea? Did you read Ticket to
Boothill? Zack Morgan was in a showdown
against the Seven Taggart Brothers.
Wait a minute.
Isn't Zack Morgan dead?
There's no one alive who could have
killed Zack Morgan.
Let's go play Zack Morgan, U .S.
Marshal.
Yee -haw! Come on, let's go!
Dirty farming?
Stay back!
You're dead!
I'll be back.
Hey, wait for me. Hello, sir.
So, Felicity...
Which way are you heading?
We were just going to look at... I have
no particular plans.
Why not walk with me?
That sounds delightful.
Aunt Hetty?
Aunt Hetty, I'm home.
Aunt Hattie?
Oh, Sarah, it's you. You startled me.
Oh, goodness, child. You mustn't creep
up on people like that.
Sorry.
Oh, what is it, dear?
I thought we were going to plan the
garden for next year.
Felicity says it's not too soon.
Oh, no, she's quite right. The garden,
yes.
It's just I need a few moments to myself
right now.
I understand.
We'll find time to spend together, I
promise.
Later in the week.
Garden completely forgotten.
Suppose somebody took a wrong turn at
Tombstone?
Marshal. Everyone knows those U .S.
Marshals were peace officers one week
outlaws the next.
All depending on which side of the law
was paying the best wages. According to
Ned Bunkline's book, Zack Morgan is
renowned for his devotion to justice.
Yes, well, his dime novels are nothing
but adventure stories for the overheated
imagination of young boys.
I had no idea a Marshal could look so...
So distinguished.
Well, the show seems like it's saying
better days to me.
Don't you encourage him, Olivia Dale?
Rachel, my interest is purely
professional.
I'd just love to get an interview with
him for the Chronicle.
If he comes one step closer, I'm
leaving.
Good afternoon, ladies.
Good day, Marshal.
I couldn't help notice you standing
here. I thought I might take this
opportunity to invite you to our first
performance.
Why, thank you. That would be
delightful.
Marshal? Is it?
Well, forgive me.
U .S. Marshal Zack Morgan at your
service, ma 'am.
And you are?
Rachel Mabel.
And I'm Olivia Dale of the Avonlea
Chronicle.
Well, you can call me Zack, Miss Dale.
I'm retired now.
Aunt Olivia, I've been looking for you.
Sarah, meet Marshall Morgan.
This is my niece, Sarah Stanley.
Niece? Well, I'd have taken you two for
sisters.
Sarah.
You know that's my favorite name?
Well, it was a pleasure, ladies. I hope
you'll excuse me, but I do believe we
have some work to do.
I hope I'll be seeing you again, Matt.
Sarah?
He's certainly a fascinating gentleman,
isn't he, Sarah?
Sarah?
Oh.
Yes.
He's no such thing, Olivia Dale.
He's a cowpoke.
That's what.
That doesn't really look like him.
You're not... saying he's just
pretending to be a U .S. Marshal.
Well, I... This photo is in 1888, and
the Marshal had been catching outlaws
seven years.
He was a captain in the cavalry before.
Is that where he learned to shoot?
Nope, he was a Deadeye at age ten.
I believe it.
It says here that he can draw as gun
faster than a rattler can strike.
I bet he can draw in fire in two -tenths
of a second.
Hey, do you think the Marshal will draw
the show?
I saw him practicing some spectacular
tricks.
Morning, Mrs. Lawson. Oh, good morning.
There he is.
The whole town is excited about your
show, especially the children.
I only have a dime.
What should I get?
Let it done or hire out to danger. They
haven't stopped reading your book.
My pleasure, ma 'am. You know what it's
about.
I'd like to thank you, ma 'am, for
taking our display.
Looks like I should thank you.
Boys, Izzy, put those books back.
Now, if you want to read them, you've
got to buy them. This is a store, not a
lending library.
You bring any books you buy out to the
show and Zach will sign them for you.
another thing.
This Saturday night at the last show,
we're going to have a barrel race.
And you're all eligible to enter.
Is there a prize?
Of course there's a prize.
The winner gets a genuine eagle feather
from Crazy Horse of Tedris.
Gave it to me personally.
You all right?
I'm fine, thank you. Are you?
I hope I didn't hurt you when I fell.
I should have pushed the door open.
Well, just hold on, young lady. It's my
fault. I'm the one who opened the door.
No.
I'm all right, thank you.
Well, I hope you're feeling all right
enough to come see our first show.
Wild horses couldn't keep me away.
Well, that's good.
Ma 'am?
Everybody knows the Earps didn't clean
up Dodge City.
Zack Morgan did it. But going after the
hole -in -the -wall gang.
Single -handed.
Now that took courage.
What about the time he faced down Billy
the Kid?
Unarmed. Billy the Kid.
Howdy, boys.
Wonder if one of you might be able to do
me a favor.
I'll do anything.
There's been talk that I've lost a
little speed on my draw What I'd like to
what I'd like to do is just to try out a
little test here You hold that please
What I want you to do is just hold your
hands like this, okay?
Just like that now this could be a might
dangerous Now whenever you're ready
what I want you to do is clap your hands
that's it clap
Whenever you're ready.
Oh, did you see that?
Oh, that was too fast to see. Well,
guess I haven't lost that much speed
all.
Thank you, boys.
Ma 'am?
I have to see him again.
Well, then just go down to the tent.
Everyone in town's been there.
That's no good.
I don't just want to see him again.
I want to get to know him better.
I want him to know me.
There's Stanley.
But he's so much older, don't you think?
Listen, I'm fed up with boys.
That Morgan is...
But sure.
Well, he does have that in his favor.
Not to mention he looks like a Greek
god.
Have you said anything to him?
Of course not. I only met him yesterday.
Well, you have to get his attention.
What do I do?
Take some research.
We charge nothing for our historical
demonstrations, not one red cent.
But I'm about to offer you a once -in -a
-lifetime opportunity. This genuine
shell casing from the Battle of the
Little Big Horn.
By the darn thing, Archie Gillis, I'll
lend you the two bits. A trophy
personally collected by Marshal Zack
Morgan, the only survivor of General
Custer's army. The bullet couldn't
penetrate his thick hide, but he lay
unconscious.
For three days.
All right, all right, I'll take it.
Thank you, sir. And remember, this is
only a hint of what you'll see Saturday
night.
Are you ready, Marshal? Ready.
Are you ready, Kitty?
I have to spend more time with them.
But how?
I don't know what else to do.
Well, Gus told me that all the boys were
practicing for a Wild West horse show.
Sarah, it's perfect.
How do you mean?
Well, you'll practice on Aunt Hedy's
horse, make it look like you had an
accident, and the marshal will suddenly
see your delicate figure crumpled on the
ground. He'll rush over to me and take
me into his arm.
It's so kind of you, Jack, taking all
this time to help me.
One thing's for sure.
You ain't got to win this race sitting
on that little English saddle of yours.
You ready to give it a try?
I think so.
All right.
Now, the whole secret is to control her
with your knees as well as your hands,
all right?
Okay.
Well, don't try to talk and don't try to
move.
Fall like this can be worse than you
think.
You must be thirsty. Would you like some
lemonade?
Well, maybe just a glass. I think I
should stay to reassure your aunt that
weren't hurt.
All right, then make yourself
comfortable. Go get the lemonade.
All right.
See, it worked.
Just like I said.
What do I do now, though? I mean, what
do I say to him?
Ask him about himself.
Men like that.
It must be so exciting to travel.
I bet you've seen things most people can
only dream about.
Well, that is a fact, Sarah.
I reckon I got friends scattered all the
way from Paris to San Francisco.
You're not leaving already, are you? No,
I was just going to go help myself to
some more lemonade.
No.
I mean, I'll get it for you. No, no, you
stay right there.
You took quite a fall.
Did he see you? No.
But Aunt Hattie's coming. Aunt Hattie.
I'm afraid you're going to have to leave
now.
I thought you wanted me to stay.
Well, something's just come up. Like a
flash flood on the Cheyenne Trail.
I was only gone a minute.
I don't think that my aunt would approve
if she came home and found you here.
Well, why don't you let me explain it to
her, all right?
Oh, do forgive me. That coach from
Carmody.
Marshall.
This is a surprise.
Well, I know just how you feel, ma 'am.
I didn't realize Sarah had two aunts.
Aunt Heavy, would you like some
If you are referring to Olivia, she
happens to be my younger sister.
No.
Well, not more than by just a couple of
years, ma 'am.
What?
Oh, yes, well, people do quite often
remark on our close resemblance.
Now that you're here, Marshal, surely
you'll stay, have a glass of lemonade or
something. Well, thank you very much, ma
'am, but I can't stay. I'd like to, but
I've got to get back on down to the
fairgrounds. I've got plenty of work to
I just wanted to make sure that the
little girl was all right.
All right.
What do you mean?
What happened to us?
Men are a trial, Sarah. Get used to it.
I'm not a little girl.
Why can't he just see what's in front of
his face?
Is that so difficult?
That's what makes them men.
How much time do we have?
Probably not enough time to make Zack
Morgan realize I'm a woman.
Drastic times call for drastic measures.
I think we'll start with your hair.
And then we'll have to make you
something exquisite to wear.
Aunt Hetty? Thanks.
Oh, very imaginative, Sarah.
Quite striking, in fact.
Oh, yes, I'm sure you'll make a very
strong impression.
Daddy, is it just the stage she's going
through?
Have you seen her? She looks like a...
Well, it is the most startling
transformation.
I don't know quite what to say.
What did you say?
I said she looked charming, of course.
Yes, but... Well, I've given you my
word, Olivia, and I'll keep to it no
what. Just, I never dreamt she'd turn
out like this.
you, Hedy, but it really is the best
way.
You just accept her behavior.
Why stop there?
Why not encourage it?
Why not invite the man to tea at Rose
Cottage? Hedy, that's a marvelous
idea. Are you joking?
Well, no. Think of it.
Well, Zach Morgan is quite charming.
Sarah would...
See that you support her, and at the
same time, you would be able to keep an
on development.
Ah.
You look like a real cowgirl.
Thank you.
So you're off to do your interview
with... Zack Morgan.
I was wondering, if I promised to stay
out of your way, could I come with you?
Sure. I don't see why not.
The spirit of the Wild West certainly
has infected our town.
Off we go.
It's wonderful that you've taken such a
keen interest in riding, Sarah.
Morning. Morning.
Sarah, I want you to meet Pepper.
She is beautiful.
I thought you might like to know what it
feels like to ride a real cow pony.
Couldn't. Well, sure you can.
Go on, stretch your legs. She's quick
and she's smart.
Can I really?
Go on.
It looks like Sarah.
Sarah Stanley?
Would you look at that?
Where'd you ever learn to do that?
You don't learn to do that.
You must have been born on a horse.
Your niece is quite a little
firecracker.
I'm sure it'll make a good story for
you.
She's sure to surprise those boys come
Saturday night.
Oh, it's not something she hasn't done
before.
When Sarah sets her mind to something,
there's no stopping her.
Well, I reckon she's a lot like her aunt
in that respect.
Well, now tell me, where did you get the
idea to start a Wild West show?
Well, I have to confess, I got the idea
from my old friend Bill Cody.
Buffalo Bill?
Here he is in the flesh, Marshal Zach
Morgan. Let me introduce Mr. Calvin
of the Charlottetown Gleaner.
Marshal? Murphy?
Say, I've never seen that young lady
before.
Is she new?
Why, no, she's just... She spent most of
her life on a horse.
Would you believe the long -lost
daughter of Calamity Jane?
And she's only 14.
No, she's not.
I know, it's hard to believe.
Well, that's just not true.
They say her daddy is Wild Bill Hickok.
Well, that's impossible.
Do you think anybody can ride a horse
like that? You have to admit, she's one
a million.
How about an interview?
Well, she's mighty shy, but I can tell
you all about it. You come with me,
man. I'll tell you now.
What's going on here? Why is he saying
all those things?
Simon's just trying out some new ideas.
Sometimes he just gets carried away.
Fine, but Mr. Murphy's editor will have
his hide.
Well, I think he'd be happy to get a
story about the long -lost daughter of
Calamity Jane.
But it's not true.
Well, ma 'am, we call it show business.
Oh.
Well, all right.
What about you and Buffalo Bill, then?
Or were you making that up, too?
Oh, no, ma 'am.
Capers, Wesley Dale cheese. Oh, it'll be
a lovely tea, Eddie.
Oh, yes.
I hope the Marshal can appreciate it.
Oh, I know it'll be a treat for him.
Mostly Mr. Red Fox by being... Eddie
have you lost your mind?
No, I've not.
Well, if you must know Rachel Linden,
the Marshal's become quite a friend of
family, I see.
You'll get nothing but trouble by
inviting that gunslinger into your home.
Oh.
Excuse me, Rachel.
I think the blue.
The blue does bring out your color.
But I think it makes you look too
independent.
Men like to feel as though you need
them.
You have to seem rather forlorn and
wistful.
I don't know, Felicity.
Are you sure they're all the same?
Trust me.
I live with men every day of my life.
What about Gus?
We're not talking about Gus.
We're talking about Marshal Zack Morgan.
Isn't he wonderful?
He's so very dashing and so rugged,
so...
Felicity, which dress? I only have a few
minutes.
Oh, yes.
Well, I'd say the blue.
Well, then, Marshal, do you prefer the
Indian or... We have Earl Grady.
Well, I'm partial to either.
In this beautiful setting of yours, any
tea would be ambrosia, may I?
There you are.
Thank you.
Uh, shouldn't we wait for Olivia?
Oh, no, no, no.
She promised to be here. Here, lemon.
You can't always count on Aunt Olivia to
be punctual, especially not since she...
Olivia.
Oh. Oh.
Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry I'm late.
Why is that Auntie Hattie? Just think,
when he gets older, I can tell my son
that he actually met Marshall Black,
Morgan.
Oh, Olivia.
Sammy. And when climbing so poor, Mr.
Murphy, that you were Calamity Jane's
-lost daughter, well, he went for it
like a coyote to a hen house. No.
He did.
Why not? You're good enough to ride in
the show.
Serious?
Is that a fact?
Really?
Calamity Jane's daughter?
I never thought you had such a
particular talent for riding, Sarah.
Well, she's been working awfully hard,
Hetty. Riding every day.
That is impressive.
I suppose I've been so busy I hadn't
noticed.
Oh, thank you, Zach.
You're welcome.
You don't have to do that. You're the
guest.
That's the least I can do after all your
hospitality.
Besides, I like the company.
You've been awfully good with Sarah.
It's a difficult time for her right now.
All the changes that have been going on
in our lives and... Well, it's growing
up, I guess.
It's very kind of you to take an
interest in her.
Well, she's an easy child to like.
She puts her heart into everything she
does.
Oh, thanks.
But... I think that she's more than just
curious about me.
And I'm not quite sure what to do about
it.
This is no romance novel, Olivia. This
is real life.
Keeping an eye on developments, my
auntie.
She looked at that cowboy.
Daddy, I thought that was sort of sweet.
What?
Don't worry, Hetty. He's a grown man.
Don't worry.
No, I mean, he understands.
Oh, yes, but does she understand?
What he understands, that's what I want
to understand.
Good night, Harry.
I'm not saying they don't like the act.
All I'm saying is that audiences always
want something new.
This is a Wild West show, Simon. It
ain't exactly new.
We have to do something.
You saw the Crown of Kitty show?
Here.
Here's the tape for this week.
And here's this week's bills.
If we don't come up with a new gimmick,
Zack,
we'll have to close it down.
I hate to do it.
Yes.
Has to be for you.
My man only smells of sweat and beer.
When two hearts find each other in the
darkness...
No human power can keep them apart.
True love refuses to submit to its
passion, to the natural impediments of
time or distance or the unnatural
shackles of custom and manners.
From the moment I first saw your picture
on the poster, I knew, dear Zachary.
People who come from miles around to see
Calamity Jane's long -lost daughter,
you know it.
She's just a kid, Simon.
They love her.
How old were you when you left home?
I was different.
Things were different back then.
On Pepper, she'll win every race going
away.
You could teach her the shooting act.
She'd come if you asked her.
I know.
Can't do it, Simon.
I can't take her away from here.
That's the way you feel.
Just remember those bills.
If it ain't Calamity Jane's daughter, we
gotta do something.
Soon.
There was some ride you gave her this
afternoon.
She's so easy.
I love riding her.
So, you think you'd like to ride her
forever?
You mean it?
I mean, only if you'll be with us.
Of course I'd be with you.
Zach Morgan's Wild West show, isn't it?
Zach will be so happy.
You won't be sorry, I promise. Now, now,
hold your horses, hold your horses.
I didn't say yes.
Let me think about it.
What did he say?
I was so nervous I could have died.
But what did he say?
He asked me to go with him.
He said we'd be together forever.
Felicity, you have to... Promise me
you're not going to say anything.
Not to anyone.
I'll cross my heart and hope to die,
Sarah.
But are you sure?
I'm sure.
Travis Riley and Diablo,
ladies and gentlemen, the perfect team
of horse and rider.
And now... A chance for the young people
of Avonlea to relive the excitement of
the Wild West.
A barrel race.
And I think you're all going to be
mighty surprised.
Come on out here, kids.
I'm not at all sure we should let her do
this.
Let her have her fun. Once the race is
over, all the fuss will be out of your
life.
Two laps round the barrel for the
genuine eagle feather.
Everybody ready?
At the rail is Bryn Telshad on property.
Alfie Bugle on sugar.
Rupert Gillis on Barney. Rory Gleeson on
Tad. And Sarah Stanley on pepper.
Love it, babe.
It wouldn't be great as little Calamity
Jane.
always likes it what do you mean so
exciting the way everyone
looks at you the way they act no not
always you
know my my life may look exciting but no
matter where i go i'm really just a
ghost truth is marshal zach morgan
worked his whole life to build a world
really doesn't need him anymore the wild
west has been tamed
The crowd loved you.
Well, they come for a diversion, a show,
and I give it to them by pretending to
be somebody I used to be.
I can't ask you to come with me, Sarah.
I'm a walk in history book, and you have
your whole life ahead of you.
You didn't ask me.
I want to come with you.
But you have friends here.
Family. People who love you.
No.
I'm all alone.
Like you.
No. Not like me.
This... This show is not what you think.
I am not what you think.
I don't care.
Zach, I know I can help this show.
You said so yourself.
Please, Zach.
Once you set your mind to something, you
are tenacious, aren't you?
Don't you forget that, Zach Morgan.
All right.
But you get on home now so nobody
suspects.
And be back here just after sunup
because that's when we pull out.
Sarah?
Sarah.
Well, Presbyterian King, you're up
early, aren't you?
I couldn't sleep.
Anything the matter?
No, nothing's the matter. Good.
Good.
Well, I'll just cozy things up for us in
here a little bit.
Looks like you're not the only early
riser. Your cousin's up, too.
Sarah?
No.
That's impossible.
We'll follow her and we'll bring her
back.
I'm so sorry.
I never guessed that she'd do anything
like this.
There she is.
No.
What are you doing here?
He left without me.
What am I going to do?
He's a scoundrel. He's not.
You didn't really know him.
Zack Morgan is an ungrateful wretch.
Not a delight to me.
Little?
Must have looked ridiculous.
He isn't good enough to carry your bag.
My gosh and Teddy I wrote her a letter I
have to get back home and face her
You're up and about early this morning,
Sarah Stanley.
Oh, I'm sure you have your reasons,
though.
You must be hungry, child.
Come on, we'll have some breakfast,
shall we?
I'm just going to put this upstairs.
I'll be back.
Oh, all right.
Hurry back down. Don't want it to get
cold.
Oh.